export const JEWELLERYA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following is the appropriate device used as support in soldering?",
A: "Plaster of Paris",
B: "Hand vice",
C: "Lead block",
D: "Charcoal block",
answer: "C. Lead block",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The shapes used for jewellery items are technically referred to as",
A: "templates.",
B: "patterns.",
C: "motifs.",
D: "sketches.",
answer: "C. motifs.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Identify the working end of the soldering iron from the options below.",
A: "Bit",
B: "Cord",
C: "Nozzle",
D: "Hose",
answer: "A. Bit",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is a necessary factor for the preparation towards a successful exhibition of jewellery items?",
A: "Evaluation",
B: "Appreciation",
C: "Building of portfolio",
D: "Press conference",
answer: "C. Building of portfolio",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. An enamelled pendant is best cleaned with",
A: "acetone.",
B: "methylated spirit.",
C: "resin.",
D: "silver polish.",
answer: "B. methylated spirit.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. From the options below choose the technique which eases the strain in metals after hammering.",
A: "Annealing",
B: "Burnishing",
C: "Soldering",
D: "Enamelling",
answer: "A. Annealing",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following is a strong factor for locating a jewellery industry?",
A: "Identifying the customers â€˜taste",
B: "Nearness to market",
C: "Plan for workshop",
D: "Storage for raw materials and tools.",
answer: "B. Nearness to market",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following materials are classified as resists!",
A: "Asphaltum, shellac and wax",
B: "Lacquer, wax and alcohol",
C: "Turpentine, asphaltum and lacquer",
D: "Turpentine, alcohol and thinner",
answer: "A. Asphaltum, shellac and wax",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Select a major advantage of clay over stone as materials for beadmaking.",
A: "Ability to last longer",
B: "Easier to manipulate",
C: "Easier to clean",
D: "Readily marketable",
answer: "B. Easier to manipulate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Choose the reason why people acquire jewellery for keeps.",
A: "As wealth for posterity",
B: "For easy identification",
C: "To build confidence",
D: "To maintain pride",
answer: "A. As wealth for posterity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A traditional pendant, embossed with the image of a tortoise and a snail symbolizes",
A: "peace.",
B: "prosperity.",
C: "sluggishness.",
D: "victory.",
answer: "B. prosperity.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The traditional goldsmith decorates pendants through the process of",
A: "casting and cutting.",
B: "filigreeing and granulation.",
C: "filing and lacquering.",
D: "weaving and patination.",
answer: "B. filigreeing and granulation.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of these conditions facilitate annealing?",
A: "Coverage of fire on metal",
B: "Moderate heat on metal",
C: "Source of fire and metal",
D: "Thickness of metal used",
answer: "C. Source of fire and metal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Select from the options below, the characteristic nature of enamels processed for use.",
A: "Foam and slime",
B: "Lumping and pulverized",
C: "Slime and slip",
D: "Slip and liquid",
answer: "D. Slip and liquid",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following items is most suitable to be used when fixing findings to enamelled products?",
A: "Blow lamp and borax flux",
B: "Blow lamp and pin backs",
C: "Hatchet and borax flux",
D: "Hatchet and pin backs",
answer: "A. Blow lamp and borax flux",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following is the appropriate technique for decorating paper beads?",
A: "Enamelling",
B: "Etching",
C: "Patination",
D: "Stippling",
answer: "D. Stippling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. What effect will hard solder have on metal during soldering? It will",
A: "aid in pickling.",
B: "delay melting.",
C: "pre vent joining.",
D: "strengthen joints.",
answer: "D. strengthen joints.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Gold is alloyed to",
A: "become affordable.",
B: "become pure.",
C: "increase its weight.",
D: "make it workable.",
answer: "D. make it workable.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the methods in the options is used in forming glass beads?",
A: "Annealing",
B: "Casting",
C: "Firing",
D: "Polishing",
answer: "C. Firing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the materials listed below is most ideal for reducing the weight of clay beads?",
A: "Borax",
B: "Kaolin",
C: "Sand",
D: "Sawdust",
answer: "D. Sawdust",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Under which condition will a piece of leather develop moulds?",
A: "Heat",
B: "High humidity",
C: "Temperate humidity",
D: "Wind",
answer: "B. High humidity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Identify the technique which makes cloisonne enamelled jewels permanent.",
A: "Buffing",
B: "Electroplating",
C: "Glazing",
D: "Polishing",
answer: "B. Cloisonne.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Select the body adornments mostly used by traditionalist to determine the growth of a baby.",
A: "Anklet and earring",
B: "Earring and finger ring",
C: "Finger ring and waist beads",
D: "Neck chain and anklet",
answer: "A. enamel.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. From the options below, identify the major source of aluminium.",
A: "Bauxite",
B: "Copper and tin",
C: "Kaolin",
D: "Zinc and bronze",
answer: "A. Balance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following options make soldering impossible?",
A: "Application of flux",
B: "Even heating of metals",
C: "Noticable gap",
D: "Pickling of work",
answer: "C. lacquering.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The type of file which bites deeply to remove metal is the",
A: "flat file.",
B: "hand file.",
C: "knife file.",
D: "round file.",
answer: "B. easy solder, followed by soft solder and then hard solder.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Choose the most appropriate finishing technique for a bisque fired clay bead from the options.",
A: "Anodizing",
B: "Glazing",
C: "Pickling",
D: "Polishing",
answer: "C. Mandrel and piercing saw",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Traditionally, the soul of the society is symbolised by the",
A: "crown.",
B: "pendant.",
C: "stool.",
D: "sword.",
answer: "A. Fixing works on a support, security and visitors book",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the options describes analogous colour?",
A: "A mixture of three or more colour.",
B: "A reflexion of one prominent colour",
C: "Colours opposite each other on the colour wheel",
D: "Colours that lie side by side one the colour wheel",
answer: "D. Truing up an edge and shaping jewellery items.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The jewellery student uses the computer basically to",
A: "achieve high finish.",
B: "enhance creativity in design.",
C: "increase production of items.",
D: "reduce cost of production.",
answer: "D. 750/000Ag",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Bone, ivory and horn are classified as",
A: "inorganic.",
B: "mineral.",
C: "organic",
D: "synthetic.",
answer: "D. wires.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following is a safe working condition at the jewellery workshop?",
A: "Eating in the studio",
B: "Good ventilation and light",
C: "Wearing of plastic coat and goggles",
D: "Wearing of gloves and boots",
answer: "C. Pewter",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The appropriate means of removing asphaltum after etching is by",
A: "applying alcohol.",
B: "boiling.",
C: "heating.",
D: "using brine.",
answer: "D. firing in the kiln.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A bracelet is",
A: "abroad but a bangle is thin.",
B: "flexible but a bangle is rigid.",
C: "longer but a bangle is shorter.",
D: "organic but a bangle is metallic.",
answer: "C. Pounding",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A method of production, peculiar to an artist is",
A: "creativity.",
B: "composition.",
C: "style.",
D: "technique.",
answer: "A. ammonium sulphide",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The jeweller corrects most defects at the",
A: "idea development stage",
B: "pre-imaging stage.",
C: "prototype stage,",
D: "working-drawing stage.",
answer: "B. cloisonne.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following tools will be appropriate in determining the size of a wedding ring?",
A: "Blow torch",
B: "Mandrel",
C: "Rod",
D: "Scriber",
answer: "B. Ratchet brace",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following techniques is associated with lost-wax?",
A: "Chasing",
B: "Cirepedue",
C: "Cloisonne",
D: "Respousse",
answer: "A. bore holes.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. It is important to pickle the metal when fabricating a bangle to",
A: "add value.",
B: "dissolve surface oxidation.",
C: "increase the life span.",
D: "make it shine.",
answer: "C. Driving pinion",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Fasteners on bracelets and necklaces should be easy to operate to ensure",
A: "aesthetics and affordability.",
B: "affordability and reliability.",
C: "creativity and compactibility.",
D: "reliability and compactibility.",
answer: "B. ii",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]